Alan W. Steelman papers, Inclusive: 1960-2003, Bulk: 1973-1976
Baylor University, Baylor Collections of Political Materials
- Press, 1973-1976, undated; 9
  - Releases, 1973-1976; 4
    - Land Use Press Package, 1975 (Box 177, Folder 13)
    - “Late Amendment Release”, 1973 (Box 177, Folder 14)
    - “Letter to ICC About Truckers”, 1974 (Box 177, Folder 15)
    - “Letter to Roger Lewis”, 1974 (Box 177, Folder 16)
    - “Letter to Testify on Aubrey”, 1974 (Box 177, Folder 17)
    - “Mandatory Financial Impact Statement”, 1975 (Box 177, Folder 18)
    - “Mark Wells Page Announcement”, 1974 (Box 177, Folder 19)
    - “MIA’s Letter to Schlesinger”, 1973 (Box 177, Folder 20)
    - “Middle East Trip”, 1975 (Box 177, Folder 21)
    - “Military Surveillance”, 1975 (Box 177, Folder 22)
    - “Military Surveillance Bill”, 1974 (Box 177, Folder 23)
    - “Mrs. Gentry Tribute”, 1974 (Box 177, Folder 24)
    - “Navy Hearings Program”, 1976 (Box 177, Folder 25)
    - “National Park Service Letters”, 1974 (Box 177, Folder 26)
    - “Nixon Resignation Statement”, 1974 (Box 177, Folder 27)
    - “No Mandatory Retirement”, 1975 (Box 177, Folder 28)
    - “No Mandatory Retirement Bill”, 1974 (Box 177, Folder 29)
    - “Oil Shale Letter/Telegram”, 1973 (Box 177, Folder 30)
    - “Older Americans Seminar”, 1975 (Box 177, Folder 31)
    - “Older Americans Seminar”, 1974 (Box 177, Folder 32)
    - “OMB Amendment”, 1973 (Box 177, Folder 33)
    - “OMB Bill Material”, 1973 (Box 177, Folder 34)
    - “OMB Cosponsors Release”, 1973 (Box 177, Folder 35)
    - “OMB Reintroduction”, 1973 (Box 177, Folder 36)
    - “OMB Vote Statement”, 1973 (Box 177, Folder 37)
    - ‘OMBE Administration Bill”, 1976 (Box 177, Folder 38)
    - OSHA Amendment, 1974 (Box 177, Folder 39)
    - “OSHA/Capitol Inspection”, 1976 (Box 178, Folder 1)
    - “Overspending Record Statement”, 1975 (Box 178, Folder 2)
    - Pay Raise Disapproval, 1974 (Box 178, Folder 3)
    - Phase IV Statement, 1973 (Box 178, Folder 4)
    - “Pol. Committee Busing Statement”, 1975 (Box 178, Folder 5)
    - POW Congressional, 1973 (Box 178, Folder 6)
    - “Privacy Package Release”, 1974 (Box 178, Folder 7)
    - “Privacy Task Force Recommendations”, 1974 (Box 178, Folder 8)
    - “Privacy Vice Chairmanship”, 1974 (Box 178, Folder 9)
    - “Propane Letter to Simon”, 1974 (Box 178, Folder 10)
    - Property Tax Release, 1973 (Box 178, Folder 11)
    - “Pro-Rate Social Security”, 1975 (Box 178, Folder 12)
    - “Public Documents Cosponsor”, 1974 (Box 178, Folder 13)
    - “Questionaire 1976” (Box 178, Folder 14)
    - Questionnaire Release, 1973 (Box 178, Folder 15)
    - “Ranking Memberships”, 1975 (Box 178, Folder 16)
    - Rape Center Bill, 1974 (Box 178, Folder 17)
    - Re-Election Press Conference, 1974 (Box 178, Folder 18)
    - “Revenue Sharing Extension Bill”, 1975 (Box 178, Folder 19)
    - “Revenue Sharing Hearings”, 1975 (Box 178, Folder 20)
    - RCC Constituent Party Story, 1976 (Box 178, Folder 21)
    - Save Out Door America Bill, 1974 (Box 178, Folder 22)
    - “Savings Exemption Bill”, 1974 (Box 178, Folder 23)
    - “Security Classification”, 1975 (Box 178, Folder 24)
    - Security Classification Reform Bill Release, 1974 (Box 178, Folder 25)
    - ‘Select Comm. on Aging”, 1974 (Box 178, Folder 26)
    - “Senate Nomination Announcement”, 1975 (Box 178, Folder 27)
    - SER Language Letter, 1973 (Box 178, Folder 28)
    - SER Record Statement, 1973 (Box 178, Folder 29)
    - “Social Security Bills”, 1974 (Box 178, Folder 30)
    - “Social Security Commission”, 1975 (Box 178, Folder 31)
    - Social Services Bill, 1973 (Box 179, Folder 1)
    - Soviet Jew Press Conference, 1973 (Box 179, Folder 2)
    - Soviet Jew Statement, 1973 (Box 179, Folder 3)
    - Soviet Jew Telegram, 1973 (Box 179, Folder 4)
    - Soviet Jew TV Statement, 1973 (Box 179, Folder 5)
    - “Spanish-Speaking Committee”, 1973 (Box 179, Folder 6)
    - “State of the Union Release”, 1973 (Box 179, Folder 7)
    - St. Louis-Dallas Amtrack Release, 1973 (Box 179, Folder 8)
    - “Sunset Testimony”, 1976 (Box 179, Folder 9)
    - “Supreme Court Decision”, 1975 (Box 179, Folder 10)
    - Summer Intern Release, 1973 (Box 179, Folder 11)
    - “Trinity Canal Appropriation”, 1975 (Box 179, Folder 12)
    - “Trinity Hearing Statement”, 1976 (Box 179, Folder 13)
    - “Trinity River Testimony”, 1975 (Box 179, Folder 14)
    - U.N. Zion Resolution, 1975 (Box 179, Folder 15)
    - Vietnam Record Statement, 1975 (Box 179, Folder 16)
    - “Ways & Means Letters”, 1976 (Box 179, Folder 17)
    - Taskforce on Aging, 1974 (Box 179, Folder 18)
    - “Task Force Release”, 1973 (Box 179, Folder 19)
    - “Ten Cent Gasoline Tax and Letter”, 1974 (Box 179, Folder 20)
    - “Terrorist Resolution”, 1974 (Box 179, Folder 21)
    - “Texas Republican Citizen”, 1974 (Box 179, Folder 22)
    - “T.F. on Economic Revitalization”, 1974 (Box 179, Folder 23)
    - “Thicket Subcommittee”, 1973 (Box 179, Folder 24)
    - Trinity Defeat Statement, 1973 (Box 179, Folder 25)
    - Trinity River Authority Grant, 1973 (Box 179, Folder 26)
    - Trinity Testifying Request, 1973 (Box 179, Folder 27)
    - TV Testimony Statement, 1974 (Box 179, Folder 28)
    - Veterans Education Bill, 1974 (Box 179, Folder 29)
    - “Veterans Tuition Supplement”, 1974 (Box 179, Folder 30)
    - “Wage/Price Controls Statement”, 1973 (Box 179, Folder 31)
    - “Wage Price Statement”, 1974 (Box 179, Folder 32)
    - “War Debts Release”, 1973 (Box 179, Folder 33)
    - “Watchdog of the Treasury Award”, 1974 (Box 179, Folder 34)
    - “Watergate Clarification”, 1973 (Box 179, Folder 35)
    - “Watergate Tapes Release”, 1973 (Box 179, Folder 36)
    - “Wilbur Mills Release”, 1973 (Box 179, Folder 37)
    - “Wiretap Bill”, 1974 (Box 179, Folder 38)
  - Topical, 1973-1975, undated; 5
    - “Meet the Member” pamphlet, undated (Box 179, Folder 39)
    - Questionnaires, 1973-1975 (Box 179, Folder 40)
    - Talking Points on Issues, 1973 (Box 179, Folder 41)
    - Texas Republican Citizen Columns, 1973 (Box 179, Folder 42)
- Speeches and Floor Statements, 1964-1976, undated; 10
  In average condition, the Speeches and Floor Statements series spans the length of Steelman's professional career before and during his time in the U.S. Congress and encompasses two subseries: Floor Statements and Speeches. The Floor Statements subseries has chronological ordering from 1973-1976 and the 1976 folder holds Steelman's appearances in the Congressional Record from that year. The Speeches subseries is in alphabetical order. His speech to the AFL-CIO and his pamphlet, "How to Be An Active Congressional Constituent" retain parts from his time as the chair of the Dallas County Republican Party.
  - Floor Statements, 1973-1976; 1
    - Statements, 1973 January-December (Box 180, Folder 1)
    - Statements, 1974 February-July (Box 180, Folder 2)
    - Statements, 1974 August-December (Box 180, Folder 3)
    - Statements, 1975 January-November (Box 180, Folder 4)
    - “Congressional Record: House of Representatives”, 1976 (Box 180, Folder 5)
  - Speeches, 1964-1975, undated; 2
    - Address to American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations, 1968 (Box 180, Folder 6)
    - “Chi Omega Day Speech”, 1973 (Box 180, Folder 7)
    - “Duke Speech”, 1973 (Box 180, Folder 8)
    - “Global Business Strategy”, undated (Box 180, Folder 9)
    - “Growth Speech: SMU”, 1973 (Box 180, Folder 10)
    - “How to Be An Active Congressional Constituent”, 1964-1969, 1971-1973 (Box 180, Folder 11)
    - “Reaction Statements”, 1975 (Box 180, Folder 12)
    - “Television Show Outlines”, 1973 (Box 180, Folder 13)
    - “The Role of Businessmen”, 1973 (Box 180, Folder 14)
    - “World Trade: The Four Tigers of Asia are Growing”, undated (Box 180, Folder 15)
- Voting Record, 1971-1976; 11
  The majority of the Voting Record series is alphabetized according to Steelman's voting on a particular topic, starting with "Aeronautics, Space" and ending with "Youth." The last four folders include the roll call votes for the 93rd and 94th Congresses. This series remains in good condition.
  - Aeronautics, Space, 1971-1975 (Box 180, Folder 16)
  - Agriculture, 1973-1975 (Box 180, Folder 17)
  - Amtrak Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 180, Folder 18)
  - Alan Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 180, Folder 19)
  - Appropriations, 1973-1975 (Box 180, Folder 20)
  - Appropriations Cuts, 1971-1973 (Box 180, Folder 21)
  - Appropriations Increases, 1971-1973 (Box 180, Folder 22)
  - Arts & Humanities, 1974 (Box 180, Folder 23)
  - Atomic Energy, 1973 (Box 180, Folder 24)
  - Business, 1971-1973 (Box 180, Folder 25)
  - Cities, 1971-1975 (Box 180, Folder 26)
  - Civil Rights, 1971-1975 (Box 181, Folder 1)
  - Cloture, 1975 (Box 181, Folder 2)
  - Communications, 1971-1975 (Box 181, Folder 3)
  - Congress, 1975 (Box 181, Folder 4)
  - Conservation, 1973 (Box 181, Folder 5)
  - Consumers, 1972-1975 (Box 181, Folder 6)
  - Crime, 1972-1974 (Box 181, Folder 7)
  - Defense, 1971-1975 (Box 181, Folder 8)
  - Economy, 1974-1975 (Box 181, Folder 9)
  - Education, 1974-1975 (Box 181, Folder 10)
  - Election, 1972-1975 (Box 181, Folder 11)
  - Energy, 1975 (Box 181, Folder 12)
  - Environment, 1971-1975 (Box 181, Folder 13)
  - Federal-State Relations, 1973 (Box 181, Folder 14)
  - Federal Workers, 1973 (Box 181, Folder 15)
  - Finance, 1973-1975 (Box 181, Folder 16)
  - Foreign Aid, 1971-1973 (Box 181, Folder 17)
  - Foreign Relations, 1974 (Box 181, Folder 18)
  - General, 1973 (Box 181, Folder 19)
  - General, 1974 (Box 181, Folder 20)
  - General, 1975 (Box 181, Folder 21)
  - General, 1973-1976 (Box 181, Folder 22)
  - Government, 1971-1974 (Box 181, Folder 23)
  - Health, 1971-1975 (Box 181, Folder 24)
  - Housing, 1972-1975 (Box 181, Folder 25)
  - Information, 1973 (Box 182, Folder 1)
  - International Affairs, 1972-1975 (Box 182, Folder 2)
  - Labor, 1971-1975 (Box 182, Folder 3)
  - Letters, 1971-1974 (Box 182, Folder 4)
  - Meeting & Strategy, 1973-1975 (Box 182, Folder 5)
  - Mining, 1971-1975 (Box 182, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper Articles, 1973-1974 (Box 182, Folder 7)
  - Nominations, 1970-1974 (Box 182, Folder 8)
  - Postal Service, 1971-1975 (Box 182, Folder 9)
  - Public Works, 1971-1975 (Box 182, Folder 10)
  - Senior Citizens, 1971-1974 (Box 182, Folder 11)
  - Social Security, 1972-1975 (Box 182, Folder 12)
  - South East Asia, 1971-1975 (Box 182, Folder 13)
  - Taxes, 1971-1975 (Box 182, Folder 14)
  - Tourism, 1973 (Box 182, Folder 15)
  - Transportation, 1972-1975 (Box 182, Folder 16)
  - Treaties, 1972-1975 (Box 182, Folder 17)
  - Veterans, 1971-1975 (Box 182, Folder 18)
  - Water Resources, 1971-1973 (Box 182, Folder 19)
  - Welfare, 1971-1975 (Box 182, Folder 20)
  - Women, 1975 (Box 182, Folder 21)
  - Youth, 1972-1975 (Box 182, Folder 22)
  - 94th Congress, Roll Call Votes (1 of 3), 1975-1976 (Box 182, Folder 23)
  - 94th Congress, Roll Call Votes (2 of 3), 1975-1976 (Box 183, Folder 1)
  - 94th Congress, Roll Call Votes (3 of 3), 1975-1976 (Box 183, Folder 2)
  - 93rd Congress, Roll Call Votes, 1973-1975 (Box 183, Folder 3)
- Audio/Visual, 1964-2001, undated; 12
  The Audio/Visual series is divided into four subseries according to alpha ordering: Contact Sheets, Interviews, Photographs, and Reel-to-Reel Tapes. Steelman's interview on WRR's Robbi Wernick Program comprises the lone piece of the Interview subseries and is on cassette tape. The Photographs largely came out of three notebooks. Portraits (including a western-style one), family photos, slides, and photographs with Presidents Gerald R. Ford and George H.W. Bush are included in the Photographs subseries. The Reel-to-Reel Tapes subseries spans the year 1973 and were Steelman's radio updates of his positions on vital issues. Most of the shows are monthly episodes. Yellow official Congressional envelopes marked with a shortened version of the program title originally stored the reel-to-reel tapes (and one audio cassette)
  Cassette tape; Photo negative; Photographic print; Portrait photograph; Reel to reel tapes
  - Contact Sheets, undated; 1
    - General, undated (Box 183, Folder 4)
  - Interviews, 1975; 2
    - WRR Robbi Wernick Program & G. Oldham, 1975 (Box 183, Folder 5)
  - Photographs, 1964-2001, undated; 3
    Photo negative; Photographic print; Portrait photograph
    - Alexander Proudfoot Company, undated (Box 183, Folder 6)
    - Campaign, 1972 (Box 183, Folder 7)
    - Congressional Baseball Game, 1973-1974 (Box 183, Folder 8)
    - Congressional Term (1 of 4), undated (Box 183, Folder 9)
    - Congressional Term (2 of 4), undated (Box 183, Folder 10)
    - Congressional Term (3 of 4), undated (Box 183, Folder 11)
    - Congressional Term (4 of 4), undated (Box 184, Folder 1)
    - General, 1973 (Box 184, Folder 2)
    - General, 1974 (Box 184, Folder 3)
    - General, 1975 (Box 184, Folder 4)
    - General, 1976 (Box 184, Folder 5)
    - Negatives, 1973 (Box 184, Folder 6)
    - Negatives, 1972-1974 (Box 184, Folder 7)
    - Nixon Oval Office, undated (Box 184, Folder 8)
    - Official Congressional, undated (Box 184, Folder 9)
    - Personal, undated (Box 184, Folder 10)
    - Personal, 1980-2001 (Box 184, Folder 11)
    - Portfolio For TV Commercials, 1964-1969 (Box 184, Folder 12)
    - Portraits, undated (Box 184, Folder 13)
    - Portraits, Western, 1975 (Box 184, Folder 14)
    - Rodeo, undated (Box 184, Folder 15)
    - Slides, 1973-1974 (Box 184, Folder 16)
    - Visiting Schools, 1974 (Box 185, Folder 1)
    - With George H.W. Bush, undated (Box 185, Folder 2)
    - With President Ford, undated (Box 185, Folder 3)
    - WTC Dedication, undated (Box 185, Folder 4)
  - Reel-to-Reel Tapes, 1973, undated; 4
    Cassette tape; Reel to reel tapes
    - Program Listing/Transcripts, 1973 (Box 185, Folder 5)
    - Alaskan Pipeline, 1973 July (Box 185, Folder 6)
    - AMTRAK, 1973 February (Box 185, Folder 7)
    - Arab-Israeli, undated (Box 185, Folder 8)
    - August Recess, 1973 September (Box 185, Folder 9)
    - Beef Freeze, 1973 August (Box 186, Folder 1)
    - Big Thicket, undated (Box 186, Folder 2)
    - Big Thicket Hearings, 1973 July (Box 186, Folder 3)
    - Big Thicket Mark-Up, 1973 October (Box 186, Folder 4)
    - Cambodia Cutoff, 1973 October (Box 186, Folder 5)
    - Casework, 1973 September (Box 187, Folder 1)
    - Congressional Energy Measures, 1973 December (Box 187, Folder 2)
    - “Day in the Life”, undated (Box 187, Folder 3)
    - Drug Abuse in Schools, 1973 July (Box 187, Folder 4)
    - Election Reform, 1973 June (Box 187, Folder 5)
    - End of Year Wrap-Up, 1973 December (Box 187, Folder 6)
    - Energy, undated (Box 188, Folder 1)
    - Energy Crisis, 1973 August (Box 188, Folder 2)
    - Federal Budget, 1973 February (Box 188, Folder 3)
    - Future of the Trinity, 1973 April (Box 188, Folder 4)
    - Gasoline Storage, 1973 December (Box 188, Folder 5)
    - Impeachment Stand, 1973 October (Box 188, Folder 6)
    - Issues in Mail, Amnesty, HEW, undated (Box 189, Folder 1)
    - Mass Transit, Dallas, undated (Box 189, Folder 2)
    - Middle East Oil Situation, 1973 November (Box 189, Folder 3)
    - Mobile Office, 1973 October (Box 189, Folder 4)
    - NFL Blackout, 1973 September (Box 189, Folder 5)
    - Pension Reform, 1973 July (Box 189, Folder 6)
    - Phase IV Comment, 1973 August (Box 190, Folder 1)
    - President’s Energy Message, 1973 November (Box 190, Folder 2)
    - Questionnaire, 1973 March (Box 190, Folder 3)
    - Questionnaire Comments, 1973 April (Box 190, Folder 4)
    - Questionnaire Results, 1973 June (Box 190, Folder 5)
    - Social Security, 1973 June (Box 190, Folder 6)
    - Soviet Jews, 1973 October (Box 191, Folder 1)
    - State of the Union, 1973 September (Box 191, Folder 2)
    - Summer Intern, 1973 June (Box 191, Folder 3)
    - Tax Reform, 1973 May (Box 191, Folder 4)
    - Trade Reform, 1973 May (Box 191, Folder 5)
    - Upcoming Legislation, undated (Box 191, Folder 6)
    - Wage and Price Controls, 1973 April (Box 192, Folder 1)
    - War Powers, 1973 May (Box 192, Folder 2)
    - Watergate, 1973 May (Box 192, Folder 3)
    - 8-Month Wrap-Up, 1973 August (Box 192, Folder 4)
- Clippings, 1966-2002; 13
  The Clippings series contains four subseries: General, House Campaign, News Clippings Scrapbooks, and Senate Campaign. The General subseries was in the original inventory but the other three were created during processing. Steelman's post-Congressional work with the Alexander Proudfoot Company in 1989-1990 and the Dallas Council for World Affairs in 2000-2002 is highlighted in the General subseries, as is his pre-Congressional leadership of the Wyly Foundation (1969) and the Dallas County Republican Party (1966-1968). The House Campaign subseries is divided in three groups of months while the Senate Campaign subseries has three separate articles. Subdivided by year, the News Clippings Scrapbooks are in oversized boxes. This series is in good condition and most of the clippings have been copied.
  - General, 1966-2002; 1
    - Alexander Proudfoot Co., 1989-1990 (Box 193, Folder 1)
    - Dallas County Republican Party, 1966-1968 (Box 193, Folder 2)
    - “Definitely a comer”, 1973 (Box 193, Folder 3)
    - President’s Advisory Council OMBE, 1970-1971 (Box 193, Folder 4)
    - World Affairs Council of Greater Dallas, 2000-2002 (Box 193, Folder 5)
    - Wyly Foundation, 1969 (Box 193, Folder 6)
  - House Campaign, 1972; 2
    - General, 1972 January-June (Box 193, Folder 7)
    - General, 1972 June-July (Box 193, Folder 8)
    - General, 1972 October-November (Box 193, Folder 9)
  - News Clippings Scrapbooks, 1973-1976; 3
    - Scrapbook, Volume 1, 1974 (Box 196 OVZ)
    - Scrapbook, Volume 2, 1974 (Box 196 OVZ)
    - Scrapbook, 1973 (Box 197 OVZ)
    - Scrapbook, 1976 (Box 197 OVZ)
    - Scrapbook, Volume 1, 1975 (Box 198 OVZ)
    - Scrapbook, Volume 2, 1975 (Box 198 OVZ)
  - Senate Campaign, 1975-1976; 4
    - “Leftovers”, 1976 (Box 193, Folder 10)
    - “Steelman plansEL”, 1975 (Box 193, Folder 11)
    - “Steelman wagingEL”, 1976 (Box 193, Folder 12)
- Casework, 1973-1976; 14
  This series is alphabetically ordered by last name of the constituent. During processing, various pieces of casework were moved to other series, mostly the 94th Congress subseries. Contact an archivist for access to this series. This series is in good condition.
  - A-D, 1975-1976 (Box 194, Folder 1)
  - D-G, 1975-1976 (Box 194, Folder 2)
  - H-M, 1976 (Box 194, Folder 3)
  - N-Z (1 of 6), 1975-1976 (Box 194, Folder 4)
  - N-Z (2 of 6), 1975-1976 (Box 194, Folder 5)
  - N-Z (3 of 6), 1975-1976 (Box 194, Folder 6)
  - N-Z (4 of 6), 1975-1976 (Box 194, Folder 7)
  - N-Z (5 of 6), 1975-1976 (Box 195, Folder 1)
  - N-Z (6 of 6), 1975-1976 (Box 195, Folder 2)
  - General (1 of 2), 1976 (Box 195, Folder 3)
  - General (2 of 2), 1976 (Box 195, Folder 4)
  - Vietnam Refugees, 1975-1976 (Box 195, Folder 5)